So it feels like maybe we in corporate
don't directly touch the community
but what I see is that my customers are
spread across all points in big cities
and small towns so that's what I feel the
difference is in the company but the
flow of funds the impact of what they
build is all contributing to the
country and society
I once met someone who was
previously an
individual customer but I knew he
had skills I invited the team
to try to discuss with him
Then he had the desire to
develop his skills into
a business we tried to support the business
and Until now
he has improved his standard of living not
only for himself but for
his family so as CEO of the
Brands we can provide
financial solutions to them so as to help the
surrounding community to level up So
we both have eh passion
and strong Purpose for what
we can contribute through
what we do most happy
when what we do can have an
impact on others because at
that time we visited one of the
debtors who initially had quite large
transactions but suddenly
e started to experience a decline like that
His father said Initially when he was
experiencing covid one family who
spent a total of hundreds
Actually he had started to feel ee
almost  gave up then after
we provided financing at that time
his father was able to turn the business around
again because of what Because we encouraged
him to continue
his trading transactions and finally he was able to
run his business again normally
this is like a feeling of fulfillment that
cannot be bought with
money well besides me getting
that knowledge while working I also
realized his dream of being able to
study abroad in
2020 ago I had the opportunity
to take a Master's degree, namely an MBA in
Spain at the same year
I continued for 6 months in the US at DU
University we in the early days of creating
livin that was working without counting time there was
joy and there was pride
because the joy first my friends
here were very supportive we
really brainstormed
together like that So no one felt like
I was a senior I was not a senior like that but
there we I felt like Yes we are
together we made this together
we want this to be successful together and
Once it is successful and Once it is
public it has been used by
all friends in Indonesian society it feels
like this yes it turns out that This is how it
feels when our work can be useful
For people
like that, before joining Bank Mandiri,
I saw that start-ups were more
interesting than state-owned companies, but in
the end, when I joined here, Bank
Mandiri was truly able to provide
challenges through the Livin by
Mandiri application with active Livin users
reaching almost 12 million users
used by customers. They always
asked, is this really what
Mandiri itself developed internally? I was there
with B, answering, is this really an application
developed by Bank
Mandiri internally? In the digital world, we
cannot continue to use old standards,
we must continue to adapt and
continue to learn and implement
new technologies.
With Smart BR,
banking activities have become easier. We
provide solutions for the community.
Previously, people had to come to the
branch, had to queue, had to wait a
long time. Now everything has been
integrated through the BWM system. It
functions as an Agent of
Development because BMN
means a state-owned enterprise and
the results will later contribute to
this country. It's not just about
company targets, but we contribute
directly to the
community. [Music] Every journey starts
from a
dream.
Big dreams towards our own future.
[Music]
Our path, our destination,
our choice to keep
fighting and never
[Music]
give up
on developing.  and show the
world that losing is not an
option and determination is not something to be
played with solutions can come from
various
sides even from something unpredictable
[Music]
and sharing that spirit
has become
[Music] a
mission for us young people to have a
dream a company that is able to survive
in the long term is one that is adaptive
to the changing times in 1746
Pegadaian was first brought by the
VOC trading association the history of Pegadaian continues to change
over time and the development of conditions
even though it was deactivated the origin of
Pegadaian did not exist in Indonesian society at
that time until April 1, 1901 Pegadaian was
officially established as a state company
in
Sukabi time continues to change
after change the status of the company continues to be
carried out according to the dynamics of the
times
Pegadaian also remains consistent in
its function to serve the
community [Music] the milestone of the transformation of
pawnshops began in
1990 with the status of a general center,
moving into a
business institution until in 2012 Pegadaian
was confirmed as a limited company
now Pegadaian has grown into an
agile company with a variety of
consistent innovations and
[Music]
Sustainably carrying the vision of becoming
the most valuable financial company in
Indonesia and as the financial inclusion agent of
choice for the community
Pegadaian continues to carry out
cultural and digital transformation In accordance with
technological developments and
customer needs, moral culture is established
as the values ​​that guide
all Pegadaian personnel working in the
company and in
society Sara is the
Gistar transformation strategy implemented
to face the challenges of a business that
continues to move dynamically Pegadaian also
continues to utilize the latest information technology
to simplify business processes
and expand distribution channels
digitally by utilizing various
applications supported by
professional, competent and
cultured human resources the company is committed
to continuing to provide financial services and
solutions for the community
[Music]
with a distribution network that is
widespread in various regions of Indonesia
Pegadaian continues to serve various
groups of people even to
remote areas now products and services are
increasingly easily accessible at thousands of agents
and Pegadaian applications
[Music]
Pegadaian's digital inclusive services are spread
throughout
Indonesia not only from various
age ranges but also serve various
professions various efforts made
show
encouraging results this is evidenced by the
company's healthy performance and
stable business both from the operational
and
financial side Pegadaian consistently
contributes to the country
for Indonesia's economic development
as a form
community service Pegadaian also has a
program that not only provides
education but also improves the welfare of the community
[Music]
Pegadaian's positive performance has also
received appreciation from various parties
as recognition of the
company's reputation
[Music]
Our success is proof of
determination and hard work at a young age is
our provision to continue realizing dreams
not only stopping there but
helping the bright future that we are
aiming for
[Music] [Music
]
[Applause]
[Music]
Assalamualaikum warahmatullahi
wabarakatuh Peace be upon us
all Shalom Om Swastiastu Namu Buda and
greetings of virtue Good afternoon
everyone welcome to the UI career
internship scholarship and
entrepreneurship event or uichis Expo
2023 prepare your future Career right
now How are you all ladies and
gentlemen I hope everyone is
in good health and still
enthusiastic of course let me introduce myself Zata
who will guide the UI Kier
internship scholarship and
entrepreneurship event in the u company
talk session with fbd insurance adting your
first with essal skills
and before that Let me
introduce our event today
uic is  annual expo activity
organized by the
University of Indonesia graduate career development center or
CDC UI under the Directorate of
Graduate Career Development and Alumni Relations of
the University of Indonesia or dpkh aui
in collaboration with the alumni association of
the University of Indonesia, Center of
Independent Learning UI and Carer Lab
as an information technology platform
UI job fair in October 2023 took place from
September 25 to October 20,
2023 and was attended by various
well-known companies in addition
there was also an Expo held
offline on October 13 to 14
at the UI hall there were
various activities that colleagues could
participate in such as industry boot
camp training and also what we are currently
carrying out, namely company talk
this series of activities aims for colleagues to get
to know the company further and
prepare themselves Therefore, let's
make sure or register at
uichise.cerlab.go as
previously mentioned uicis Expo 2023 also
collaborates with Career Lab which
is a Solution platformer that
provides support to
fresh graduate students and young professionals to
prepare for careers as well as curated job fairs
for entry level Career
Lab has also supported dozens of campuses
in Indonesia with a career management
platform for centers  career and students
to find out various information about
events and other groups, colleagues can
explore further on
karirlab.g In addition, the smooth running of uiso
2023 cannot be separated from
the support of sponsors and media partners.
We would like to thank the
sponsors of is Expo 2023, namely Bang m
Niaga paragam Technology and Innovation
PT Pegadaian Bank Danamon Bank Mandiri
and our media partners, namely Media
Indonesia medcom.id Metro TV on top
ditiedu infobinar Indonesia good site
loer Bandung infocker Jobs agang info
and startup friends
next we move on to the series of
events Next before we move on to the
next series of events, I don't
forget to inform
colleagues who are present
this afternoon to confirm their attendance
via the QR Code displayed on the
following slide or you can also click on
the link sent by the committee in the
chat column In addition, at the end of
the event, a feedback form link will also be distributed
which colleagues must fill in.
Filling in this feedback form is very
important because it will be a requirement
to obtain the
next certificate in
this session I also want to invite colleagues
to take part in the uic company talk
challenge where colleagues have
the opportunity to win an
e-wallet balance worth  Rp50,000 for two
lucky participants in each session, the method is
very easy, friends can
review your favorite company talk on
Instagram Story and don't forget to
make it as interesting as possible, then
don't forget to follow and also mention the
@karirlb account. Then for the general announcement of the
winners will be announced via instaory
@carier laab every day at
night, so don't miss it,
friends, you can join
this challenge, well, the ISE events
that were conveyed are interesting, so friends, don't
forget to join after getting acquainted
with the
ISE career lab and also
interesting events, I'm sure you
can't wait to join session a
this time, maybe you guys here often
see the colorful building in SCBD
or even you guys have photos of
the building. Well, we really want
to see this building in SCBD, so
this time we will be with
fbd insurance, which is one of the
leading insurance companies in Asia Pacific, in
our session with F insurance
this afternoon, we will have two sessions,
namely the first is about financial
literacy
gen with michaellow, then there will
also be Bertan
ad SK
with  saku
op and
also
as man
fbur
nah Med insurance this afternoon the
first one we will be accompanied by Mr.
Michael Ade Wibowo as regional
trainer FD insurance Good afternoon Mr.
Michael Good afternoon Ms. Sata Okay this is
ready yes sir eh to eh provide
material about Jen money sense of
course very ready Okay extraordinary
then for the first one ee the
first session I will give directly
to mas Michel eh please Mas
thank you Eh Hello all my friends I
ask permission to call my friends because
maybe we are the same age Amen
so today I am very happy to be able to
gather together with my friends eh in
this afternoon yes Eh I am sure that in the
future we will have an
extraordinary opportunity but allow me to also
share something that maybe
a few years ago I was also
confused because talking about the future
talking about preparing for the future
Not only ee the chosen career or the
chosen profession or what business
but also preparing the money also what we
have to do because of that in
this afternoon maybe with a title like this it
will make it easier for us because
the goal is on  when
all my friends can follow the
whole event, my friends can get
Insight and my friends can immediately put it
into practice and of course it will be
useful for all my friends Okay
so today I want to share
about
moneyet something that
my friends actually understand something that is
familiar because it is always held but
sometimes it is difficult to understand like that Yes well but
before going into that eh allow me once
again My name is Michael just call me Mike
like that And maybe it can be on the next
slide Okay friends, does anyone know
or does anyone know this
person or a figure yes the one in
front of you is actually
very famous like that yes he is a
legend in the world of sports yes if you know it
already known e what he wears yes
wears boxing gloves definitely not e goal no not
also basketball but must be boxing
yes he is eh his name is Mike tson
and no one does not know him
so coincidentally his name is the same but
his fate is different from mine so
throughout his career Eh this Mikeson
can make a lot of money
yes equivalent to 4.5t may next but
friends what is interesting is not
not talking about how much but
there is a moment where he experienced a
downfall yes Even in the year  2003 Mike
Tyson stated that he was
bankrupt friends and not only was he
bankrupt but he stated that
he had a Hut
ee eh his debt was how much was
30 million US dollars or the equivalent of 450 billion
maybe now yeah Well
today I think this story is very close
friends yeah If maybe
friends see on social media there are so
many
people today are entangled in
what is called debt too, I don't know why
or maybe from the management
or maybe from ee the needs
we can't meet each other
but today maybe
if what is related to us
debt that is very close to us
today is pinjol yes
online loans which it turns out that suddenly many
of us all generation Z who
have to struggle with that
well can next
slide because that friends instead of
us just thinking about E or deciding
we look for the best work we want to
have the best future e
So friends actually I'm sure
yes we all can make as much money as possible
Whatever the way is,
whatever it is, when the time comes but if
can't manage it then there will always be
a deficit even maybe if I may
speak a little bit sharp
maybe will always feel poor
friends apologize
because Earning money with management is
something different because of that Let's
start to understand the
basic things first related to money may
next
slide Okay so the question is
Not only preparing How is
our future but how do we
fund we also have a future
next slide Well friends now
the question is that maybe
friends can answer it may also be through the
Chat column too yes let's liven up the
chat column according to friends what is money what is
money currently that
friends understand understand roughly
What is a transaction tool thank you thank
you Eh Kirina yes money is a means of
payment that is recognized right then
what else Piona maybe there are
other friends may have ideas about
money is may next
slide Is money
next something figure that comes and goes
come and go or is it
something that we have to look after or
something that has to be spent immediately
Well so of course we need to answer this
first because what was answered by
friends was exactly correct that is
written in the existing literature
money is like that but how do
we treat that money
more appropriately because of that I have an
analogy friends yes In my opinion, I
think money
is like a
cow okay Well, if friends ee
maybe have studied that
or have read or studied
the character of a cow like that Why is that,
but Okay, let's try to get into
this cow ee what is it, a cow, a
cow, a
unique animal, so this cow has a tendency
that it will like to look for
greener land so when it is
at a point where the land
is no longer green, it looks for the
neighbor's grass, that's why it always
says that the neighbor's grass is always
greener, it will always look for that
Well, because of that, if someone has a
cow at that time, friends, if they have a
cattle farm, they can't just
leave it in the field because they
don't know where to run, friends,
because of that, I think next slide if
friends have a cow, then what is needed
is a fence,
friends, this fence is what we
know that these two stories alone from
here We already understand that
money is its legs 1000
friends He  will look for a
greener place that he likes more, that's
why we need to fence him with a fence.
This is what is called
risk management. Well, from this fence,
after we fence him so that the cow
doesn't go anywhere, then we think about what to
do with the cow, okay? Next, next, are we
going to
slaughter the cow, right? Next, we
sell the meat or the cow? Well,
we just
sell it, right? Or we breed it.
Well, this last analogy is
how friends want to manage
money, right? You want to spend it, that's all, right?
That's
all your money, right? You want to change
its form and then sell it for a
greater value, right? Or maybe you could
put it in business, right? That's
also okay, that's your
friends' money or you want to
invest it somewhere, right? It's
changed its form and breed it more, more, more, more,
more.
Well, from here, friends, from
this Cow story, what we need to
understand is what money is, it turns out to be similar, yes,
money needs to be looked after, we need to
put a fence in it, which is called
risk management, after that, we think about the
money, want  Where do you go, don't go back for
money, friends, if we receive
money, what do we do with it first, then we give it a fence, so what
happens is that the money has
gone everywhere. Well, maybe
today, friends, you feel like Oh yes, that's
appropriate, sometimes if you have money, you
don't understand, suddenly it's like just come
and go, maybe the way we
treat it is that we manage it.
Dul We use it first then we give a
fence well may next slide well
the question is friends
next is then what should
we do like it or not friends
have to learn what is called
financial planning managing money like that I'm sure
friends must already know that
little by little must have
managed money but I want to
ask managing money can be written in the
chat column yes managing money or
friends have money and manage it
to be comfortable or to be safe next
again approximately safe or comfortable
friends when friends have
money what friends do to manage the
money to be safe or to be comfortable
nah comfortable Okay good laaya thank you
Reina comfortable Yes thank you is there anything else
friends approximately
safe Okay yes Ramdani so that it is safe Okay
good I'm sure friends we all
agree yes we have money we will
eventually have a large income we manage we
manage The goal is to be
comfortable I totally agree yes
friends yes I totally agree
that's the reason today friends are
preparing for the future of friends
but in the science of financial planning
it turns out there is something that we need to
shift a little may  nextide
again nah Here it is friends may
next again Yes again one more Yes nah
friends it turns out in
financial planning in managing finances or
in quotation marks managing cows earlier
friends yes the goal that we must
achieve is not comfort
first but safety first well I like
this analogy friends yes at a
time when friends may be at
a point of choice must determine
where to have a house well you may
you may later look at
the areas you will survey like that
yes you find a house that is very
comfortable ee everything is in accordance with
expectations and hopes like that yes
But do we immediately
automatically choose the house just by
the word comfortable of course not
friends will definitely
consider the duration distance the
road to get there is safe or
not it's a bit ridiculous friends
if for example we have a
comfortable house ee a good house but
getting there there are many
obstacles like that yes many
bad people like that of course we are not
comfortable like that so friends one
interesting thing
is if we want to be financially comfortable
then friends must be safe
first well how to be safe then
friends can see the most  the
bottom two are cash flow
and emergency after that go up again to
protection and management Riko now what's
interesting is that today,
many of us
manage our finances with the goal of being
comfortable in our financial goals, we
want to have a house, we want to
travel, blah blah blah blah blah,
but the fact is that it's actually used up
in the cash flow, yes, the cash flow, even though it's
only expenses and income, is actually used up
there, it hasn't
formed comfort, but it's already used up, so
instead of us not being
comfortable, we're not even safe, because of that, when
friends want to
manage their finances, pay attention to the
cash flow first, the cash flow is paid attention to and
must have an emergency fund Dul, after this
emergency fund, friends also
have to immediately have the
next security, namely protection and
mankang,
this is any place where friends can
learn, friends can also ee if
you want to play, like it was mentioned earlier, the
FBD office, you want to play, go to the office,
want to chat with friends,
FBD, we are happy to be able to
share protection and risk management
because friends when the cash flow
is good, have emergency funds, have
protection and manage risks, then the
next thing that happens
is we have what is called Peace
of Mind,
peace of
mind, friends, well, when we
are calm,
then the funds we have, we can
put into financial goals for
ourselves, friends, what do you want to buy?
Where do you want to go?
Want to please your parents, right? But
also don't forget something, friends,
namely, and in old age, I always tell you
that, friends, even if you think
about everything, there will be
one parent who is very dependent
on
you, namely yourself, in
50 years I don't know, 60 years, 30
years, there will definitely be one parent
who is very dependent on you,
namely you, right, because of that,
prepare for yourself and also of
course when you have
everything, friends, you can start to
create assets, buy land here and there,
buy gold here and there, that's possible. Okay,
next, okay, next, from
this simple financial planning, friends,
when you can
create what is called security,
comfort can be obtained because
that's what must be  What do we do
when friends already have what is
called income? Let's sort out the cash flow first, it
must be cash. Sort it out first, make sure
our expenses are not greater
than income,
then mic, if for example my expenses are
greater than income, how do I increase the
income or reduce
the expenses, well, if the expenses are
a lot, there could be debt, be careful
with debt, friends, debt is okay, debt
has its
positive side, but make sure
the debt is simple, it doesn't
make your income
minus, so make sure when
friends have debt, make sure you
can pay it off, then the second
is as early as possible,
prioritize yourself to have
income protection as soon as possible, so there is
a lot of protection, friends, there is
also a lot of risk management, there was a pager for cows, there is
also risk management, but what you need to
have today is for
friends who are still Genzi, it is
income protection. How do friends have
a
reserve to protect yourself
when you are no longer productive
and you have a reserve fund
that you can use to
replace your income, that is
income protection, so today, maybe I'll
tell you a little before I continue
next day  I was very lucky that
I was in fbd when
my condition was not good,
my condition was good, my attitude was that
when I needed
medical consultation, FD helped me, that is
income protection, otherwise what would
I
have to do with the current to
pay for medical expenses, which would ultimately
interfere with other things, I couldn't
heal, I couldn't self-reward, I couldn't do
anything else, right? Well, because the purpose
of this protection and risk management
is for you to have
your financial goals so that you can
have your finances for
your financial goals, for example, if you want to
buy a new iPhone,
make sure your cash flow is ready, have an
emergency fund, then have protection, then put it in
there, then there's the retirement fund
that you guys should also have,
at least you guys have 10%
of your total expenses set aside for your
old age, and finally, there's nothing
wrong with you guys
investing today, having
assets, right, then you guys start
thinking about how to
distribute them.
Okay,
next, okay, that's the end of
my session, guys, hopefully, of course, it's a
short session.  This can be
useful, maybe if
you want to ask,
please ask in the chat column,
we can elaborate further. Okay,
I'll return it to the moderator. Thank you
and good afternoon, okay. Okay,
thank you very much, Mr. Michel,
for the presentation of the material earlier regarding e-
gen. Okay, eh, next, for
incoming questions, you can
put them first, friends.
Uh, you can ask directly in the
Q&A column, remember in the column, not in the
chat column. So, next, we will enter the
talk session, namely regarding the
FBD insurance advisors and also for Karti
as HRBP and FBD insurance manager.
Then, for the moderator, I will also be
accompanied
by Okay, okay, maybe you can just
start right away, then
for this talk session, I will
hand it over to Ms.
[Music],
thank you for your time. Good
morning, morning,
okay, thank you, all of you,
for attending the company talk session, the
FWD session, right? And today our
topic is,
what is it called, we have
discussed it, then
after that, we will talk
about soft skills. So,
friends, what do you want to know?
worldwide working That's it, looking forward to
That's it, so what are the soft
skills needed for
friends to start their careers, friends,
what are the important ones that are
essential? So, I will
call several speakers, namely, there is
Miss, eh, as the head of operations from FWD
insurance and coincidentally, Miss Faiza is
also an alumni of UI, right Miss Hi Miss Faiza,
hello, hello, good morning everyone,
okay, besides Miss Faiza, I also
want to call, eh, what is the
name of another speaker,
maybe Miss Faiza, eh, from FWD, like,
as an employee, we also want to
see from the HR side, right? I want to
call Miss Dwi Ratna or Badwi,
Hi Badwi, hello, congratulations, if you are in
FWD, we Good morning, continue, yes, Miss Disis,
yes Good morning
everyone Morning, morning, morning, okay, then
let's
go straight to the topic, okay,
maybe I will ask some
initial questions to Miss Faizah first, okay,
Ee, regarding soft skills  So,
eh, Miss Faiza, may I know
where you first worked
and how did you start
your career? Miss Faiza, how did you get to where you are
now? The beginning of my career, yes,
professionally, I actually, when I
graduated from college, pretended to be an entrepreneur,
actually, with my friends, but
luckily I realized it quickly because I got
advice from my uncle
and maybe my friends can use it too,
that he said that if you want to be a
businessman, you can do it at any age, so
later, when you are 40,
approaching 60, you can even start a
BU, but learn to run the business.
You should learn from, eh, a
corporate or formal company. This is a corporation.
Why, because you learn leadership, learn
problem solving, how to manage many
things, so, eh, I was quite
aware. After 1 year, I finally entered
one of the state-owned enterprises, eh,
after two companies and
subsidiaries of state-owned enterprises, this is
my fourth company in
FWD. I started from the very bottom, so,
ee, I registered, ee, what's the
name, ee, claim, so it's
really from, from, from, very,
lower stock.  It was very fast, coincidentally,
Alhamdulillah, eh, the promotion was quite
fast for the standard, eh, at that time,
so until now, eh, I am the
VP or Head of Operation, fwd, eh,
the journey was quite long, eh, but
eh, if I remember it,
it was quite interesting because it was allowed, not
allowed to spill the company name, yes, it was allowed, like that.
The last one, sis,
just fwd, right? Okay, okay,
eh, I heard that Ms. Faiza
initially started a business, then after
that, eh, she immediately realized that, then after that,
finally, she entered a company, sis,
eh, what was the challenge, eh,
since you were in business, then suddenly,
what is it called, entering a corporation, eh,
what was the challenge that
Ms. Faizah faced when she first
worked, what was it like, if the first
time was adapting, eh, it was called the chain of command,
then as ee, I was raised
in a fairly democratic family,
then eh, we were always accustomed to, eh,
outspoken, what we felt, we
said, eh, do the right things, right,
eh, the white-white,
black-black, right, eh, in di
enough work ee can see that oh
the world is wide like that and and and there is a
chain of command called what we have to ee what
If there is a process eh what eh communicating
also has ethics oh there are also many friends
with
different natures like that when we were at school
we hung out with like-minded people
Kara when it comes to work just accept
people with quite
unique natures That's in terms of eh
I also happen to like learning so eh when I
first and for quite a long time at a
BUMN they happened to Cup also had
many programs for e
employee development with costs that were
also quite Royal so taking a
lot of that taking learning certifications
like that at the beginning of my career so
if you could say Eh The Advantage
of Still young already already self-
developing yourself is a
very expensive investment like that later when we are
at an age where we start to be a bit
interested here and there S lots of meetings like that it's
a bit difficult dis like that
okay that's really felt right Miss being
pulled around meetings yeah
pulled there pull here tetristi
yeah the schedule Okay so That means earlier eh
What's the name, eh, I'm aware that the challenge
is, for example, if I want to talk,
there might be bureaucracy, right, sis, you
can't just say, ee, what's the name, suddenly
talking to a superior at the same level, not just talking,
maybe there's ethics,
right, there's ethics, right,
he, and you have to keep up your knowledge,
right, sis, development, okay, okay,
because I also teach at that,
I also teach at UI, coincidentally, I
teach extension, so that's
one of the entertainments for me because meeting with
students feels like I'm back on campus,
right, even though it's not school, but
teaching,
Vi, campus is really fun for me,
that's entertainment for
workers like us, it's
out of the routine, right, sis, yaly,
I see, okay, now it means that
the world is also digital, right, sis,
Faiza, right, and eh, it's definitely
growing, so what
exactly are the skills and skill sets, right? What
other soft skills do we need to prepare
when we, eh, maybe for our friends
here, who are graduates, eh, just graduated, right,
and want to enter the world of work?
What are the important soft skills,
according to you, Ms. Faiz? There are
so many soft skills. Well, later
in the working world, without
realizing it, there are many things that have to
be completed, it turns out they are not in the book, right?
If it's an easy skill, just
take a training course, seminar, etc.
But if it's between being able to
be learned, but also if you are
talented, so from the
many, in my opinion, what is the most important one
? In the end,
we actually have to put
ourselves more on the customer's side in
any industry we work in, so more
customer-centered. That's what we have to be, eh,
at the top of our game.
Well, we provide solutions for
our customers. Again, all
industries must have customers, both
external and internal, so at the
top of our game, how do we find the
best solution for our customers? If we
work in a company, well, in
that way, we also have to have it.
The first is problem-solving
skills, right? Analytical thinking is
part of it, you have to be creative, right?
So, eh, in finding a solution
to a problem, that's what we
have to keep honing and never be
afraid of making mistakes because if you're not wrong,
you're not learning, right?  It's ok eh just take
the decision of course if you
start from the early level,
discussion with superiors with Pierce,
people who are more senior, but
that ability must continue to be honed,
so how do you do it so you can have
problem-solving skills, of
course you have to collaborate with
other friends, you have to have the skills to be
able to work in a team, teamwork,
because it's useless if you suddenly become a
champion alone, but suddenly
your teamwork is not good, because no matter
what,
eh, and whatever generation, I don't
believe that we, e, human beings,
actually need to cooperate with
other people. So teamwork is a
collaboration, you have to do that in
working, so to be collaborative,
you have to have communication skills, right?
So that's the
closest correlation in my opinion in
everyday life, e, working on top of
Later, when you grow, promotion,
you have to have leadership skills,
all of that will
develop by itself, right?
But the most important thing is
communication, problem-solving, eh, you
have to be collaborative and a good
teamwork, like that,
I see, so there were several points,
right?  Ms. Faiza, yes, it must be customer
centric, what does it mean? Eh, customer centric
means we have to find solutions for
customers, right? Eh, whatever, eh, it is
the customer, that's for sure, all companies
have it, and what are their names?
From there, we have to be able to learn problem
solving, and then we have to learn to
collaborate, right, with, eh, what are their names,
ee, other functions, like that,
okay, okay, so
what are your responsibilities right now, Ms.
Faiza, there are a lot, it
seems like I have five direct Leaders, like
senior eh Leaders, eh, the
overall team under me is more
than 140 people, like that, Ee, there are five
big departments that I, like,
coincidentally, eh, op, that's the biggest area
in this industry, so, eh, if
we say How the industry
runs a company operationally, of
course, because operationally, operations,
So, it's enough backb, Yeah, operationally,
of course, it's assisted by Finance, it's a
support function, but eh, eh, eh,
really backb, and we are
like the people who are seen
first, like, Yes, we are given a side eye first
when there are complaints, so, eh, if
there are ee  Whatever it is, the first thing to be asked is
the operation. Why is that? How can something
like that happen? How can something like this happen? So, a
heavy burden
is on my back and my team because the
Frontline is also MB, the frontline is also
in me, the customer service is like that, right?
Heeh, that's the one who deals with customers
directly, ee, there are those, Ee, We put them in,
really in, ee,
our representative offices, there are those
under my supervision, too, I see, it
means it's extraordinary, Sis Faiza,
yes, she has climbed her career from what is it
called the bottom until now she has
become Head of Operations. Well, maybe
I'll continue to Madwi first, Sis
Faiza, yes, so, eh, what is it called? Want to
see it from the HR side, right?
Sis Faiza has mentioned it, right? Some soft
skills are important in the digital world, right,
Ms. Dwi. May I ask
Ms. Dwi, eh, so, roughly, Ms., your
daily work is
recruitment, right,
Ms., from recruitment itself, if
for example, looking for candidates, what kind of candidates are you looking for,
Ms.,
okay, of course, we will adjust it first
Here's the profile that's needed by
the job that you're looking for, if it's from
the job or
from the profile that's needed regarding
customer care, then what's definitely being sought
is the profile or eh eh candidates who, eh,
besides being customer centric,
they have good customer orientation, from the soft skill side,
how can they have an attitude and
how can they show
that they have good priorities.
Well, that's certainly visible, ee, from eh,
how they represent
themselves during the interview process or
how it looks in their CV,
ee, they can include,
eh, what are the activities
they've been through or done, or
achievements in the organization, eh,
where they've been involved, so
in the interview process itself, we
can find out what the
candidate's soft skills are like, eh, so
make sure that you guys can also
represent yourself well.
and can elaborate what is
conveyed in the CV ee when in the
interview process I see means in the
interview process we also see soft
skills, right Miss I mean not only
technical skills, you
have experience eh a b CD we
see but we also see
your soft skills Ee how good is it like that well
but if for example
talking about soft skills, Miss d yeah
approximately Eh is there like the
main soft skill that maybe ee
what is it called usually seen by eh
recruiters okay the easiest to e what
identify yes the easiest to
identify in the interview process is
one communication skill how
friends
when answering or conveying
ee elaborate what e asked by an
interviewer eh that eh is
eh delivered in a good way and
eh from the communication side is understood by
the interviewee so make sure one
time in eh that is communication
skill is very eh helpful for
friends in everyday life
because eh friends when working
friends are not alone right like that
e friends work must e collaborate a lot
with various parties so
Determine how when you
communicate  or work
Eh if we talk about Genzi, of course,
eh they have a style of speaking that
might be different, there are many of them
in gen x or in baby boomer, so
how can we still adjust So
how do we adjust the way we
communicate, eh what is it called
our colleagues or to our leaders, it will
really matter, friends, because it
shows our respect, so eh communication can
we identify in the process, eh
interview, so friends, eh it is very
important for friends to be able to identify
themselves with
good communication, okay, eh So, Miss D, is
there anything that might be red, yes,
in terms of language, yes, R for
recruiters, when eh what is it called
interviewing candidates,
okay, eh in the candidate interview process,
eh usually ask questions with open
communication, yes, open questions, yes,
when we ask open
questions, usually we hope, eh, eh, to
be answered with questions that are more
explanatory, yes, not just yes or no, yes,
that's what somehow, eh, that
can also be, eh, the way to communicate, eh, is
very eh, so it does
n't make the interviewer
not understand what, eh, in eh
conveyed like that, you know, It can also
be eh, why, or it could be like this
in his CV, when he
conveys the information conveyed,
it can also be eh, what
is the initial identification for
the interviewer, they can also see whether there is
consistency or not, of course,
in the interview process, friends, ee,
you are the ones who write your CV,
make sure you
understand when ee, eh, because from there, you
can see the accuracy, there are also many things
that can be seen that can be assessed from the
CV, right, so when in the
interview process, besides one, ee, what is the name,
how is the information conveyed
in the CV, ee, and when asked
by the EE, the interviewer is all different,
and besides that, eh, the way, eh, eh,
the way the candidate communicates to the
interviewer is also very important,
friends. So, how can we
understand what you convey,
that is also important, I see, That means all
the information must be honest, yes, sis,
don't, what is the name, don't lie like that in the
CV, Yes, that's right, Sis, Dis, so it could be like this,
ma'am, in the information in the CV, I can
convey ee, what is the name, ee, in ee, on
what date until what,
did what, but it turns out  when we are
also in the process We also
do analysis too well it turns out
there is an overlap or what when
we ee do confirmation and it
turns out eh no it shouldn't be like that well
that can also show thoroughness
yeah Di yeah I because maybe this E
recruiter has a lot of flying hours too, right
Miss yes so it must be kenotis
if for example on the right there is a
slight difference like that Well if Ms. Faiza, do you
have any experience, right,
her subordinates were almost 140 like that? Do you have any
unique experience eh when eh
doing recruitment like that Miss to
look for what is called eh position below
Ms. Faiza, there are so
many
yes But it's true like eh Because
this is because we
happen to work specifically for eh
beautiful company that I follow is more on services
yeah service Well earlier eh we have
many stakeholders in Operations,
I mean eh our customers are not
only external but also internal so can you
imagine a place where
everyone asks questions usually to our area
but we can't deliver
the answers very
communicatively and clearly like that too so
so  The usual issue Well for positions,
especially if for example my direct Leaders, right
down to the manner level, it
will usually come to me too,
yeah, that's for sure, ee, the way he
communicates is what will
be eh, one of the things we point
out because imagine suddenly filling a
senior Manager position, right? Uh,
explain, try to tell me, have you ever
handled a difficult case like that,
then suddenly it's like blank, eh, eh, and
that senior Manager is like, no, that's
it, because if you're a Manager,
definitely, eh, have you had a lot of flying hours,
have handled a lot of
cases, so how can you just mention one case,
for example, if there isn't one, you can't
and can't explain it clearly
Well, we also become
like question marks, is he really doing something, is
he actually involved or
not, because if I'm in the
position of a direct Leader, I mean, I'm
already a fairly senior leader, right So,
eh, when he's managing a team,
maybe he's not involved
as a leader, so he's
not aware of what
his team is doing, maybe that's what one is
really unique, ee, like too much  unique
like that in what we want to share but
definitely what becomes an alert or Eh
this is our first Eh the way they
communicate I see So that means
eh communication skills are very
important huh Eh kakfai and also Mbak Dwi
for eh candidates huh Or
maybe friends who are just
starting their careers because
the start is from there,
friends will be assessed based on ee
How friends convey
information like how we can get
this experience of friends Or
maybe experience of friends in
organizations and others like that so
maybe that's what needs to be highlighted
friends yes communication skills are also
very important to start a career like that
eh last question
for Mbak Dwi like that eh what is it
called is it important for
candidates we see whether or not it fits
with the company culture or
maybe what is it like
Mbak we definitely see ee
Is Kab Fit with our culture because what
Because eh he will be in the organization
and collaborate with many
people of course what we eh need to
identify at the beginning is one eh
as eh what is it called the candidate
will later be  eh interaction and of course
how he can adjust because
we hope that people eh when they
are in the organization can adjust
quickly so that we can
Run together, right Well of course we will
identify one of the sides of
eh value Does this candidate
have the value that is owned by VD
for example we have the value that is eh caring
we have eh value Inova we have
eh value to be active Well of course we
will make sure to confirm this eh
in the interview process whether he has
that value or not Well so of course
friends when we eh during the
interview process eh and usually for FR
GR what we ask is
his involvement in an organization,
what is his role Well of course there you
can see eh in the process
how he interacts How
proactive is seen or not
How is he caring how
he eh what is called has Innovation Or
ideas that are conveyed or when
he is in an event are
examples where we can see
whether he is culturally Fit or
not so in the
interview process Usually we do a very Deep
interview in the process to
ensure that the candidate eh will eh Fit
in our organization
Okay noted that means indeed eh soft skills
are very important Ee  Ms. Faiza and
also Ms. Dwi because this soft skill
can also see what ee so what is
the measure like this so that's the measure e
approximately this candidate is suitable or not
with the culture in our company
also like this although later what is it called
eh from the recruiter can see it
Ee Usually because already Every
company must have its
own culture so that's from soft
skills we can identify that well this is
actually finished e usually it
seems friends if for example there are
questions let's go straight There are already a lot there are already a
lot oh how about this Ms.
Z can be answered directly or how
okay okay sis Thank you very much
for
the information earlier Ms. Faiza and also
Ms. and Ms. DIS for the Q this
will last another 3 minutes yes sis
Maybe you can dial it to me then later
I will give it back to Ms. Disti
or Ms. Faizah Budwi or Mas Michael
like that Okay so I'll try to rep up
a little bit, Ms. Zata yes So earlier
we had a little chat with
Ms. Faiza and also Ms. Dwi eh so
Friends, soft skills are very
important, friends, to start
your career, especially for you,
friends, who are fresh graduates
who are just starting
your career, so what is the
most important soft skill? Maybe one is
communication. How
can you express your
opinion well,
and how is the ethics in
communicating? And secondly, there is
problem solving, so when you are
at work, there will definitely be a lot of
challenges, challenges,
so how can you be analytical?
Your analytical thinking will be
tested there. How can you be
critical in facing the
upcoming issues, and the third one
is Working with other people,
so you won't be
working alone here, right? Ee, in a
company, you will definitely meet
various kinds of people, so you
have to be able to adapt
to the environment, how do
I communicate with
Ms. Faiza, for example, the way I communicate is different from
my communication with Madwi, so that's
different, right? How
can we work with other people too,
right?  That's all from us so if
for example friends still have
questions just e in the chat bonya
like that Yes please thank you
[Music]
friends Okay Good thank you very much
Ma'am and also Mbak Eh after listening to
the explanation earlier colleagues here
must also have known more about
fbd insurance and know the opportunities
that can be taken also been
explained about mone SS and
the importance of financial management by Mas
Michael After that we also saw the
importance of learning problem solving
collaboration and the importance of honing
soft skills to adapt to your
first landed Career yes like that Well
even though we already know but it doesn't feel satisfied
if we don't dig
deeper into the information or
opportunities offered in
this evid insurance therefore we will
immediately enter the q&a session for that
colleagues who want to ask can
submit their questions directly in the
q&a column so don't get mixed up
in the q&a column not in the chat column either
cell colleagues can also
use this q&a opportunity as best as
possible because there will be a prize for one of the
best questioners from parag technology
education will give one
attractive prize well while waiting for colleagues
to ask questions, Ma'am Mas and
also Mbak ee for colleagues who  also
want to try the opportunity to be
part of FD insurance or usually
if Geni is netizens call it
Mbak Mas or Mbak SCBD like
that yes Well, please
visit the link that has been displayed
on the screen or you can also take a screenshot
first so you don't miss the
link at
krlab.co/buf BD well not only that I
also want to invite colleagues to
monitor and register for
other upcoming u events that are no
less interesting, namely company talk with
superbank
company talk with BRI and company
talk with Bank Niaga which will
take place offline at the
University of Indonesia hall registration
colleagues can do
at.kab.co/ event does not stop
there of course there are still many
other interesting activities that can be followed from
this uicis Expo 2023 colleagues can
find hundreds of job opportunities
to get to know more closely with various
companies and scholarships as well as lots of
free training and webinars that are
open to the public for further information
colleagues can access at
uicise.carlab.g I also want to
remind colleagues not to
miss the opportunity to win an
e-wallet balance worth IDR 50,000 for
two lucky participants at  Each session is
easy, colleagues only need to
review their favorite company talk on
Instagram Story and don't forget to make it as
interesting as possible then don't forget
to follow and also mention the
@carierlab account and for the announcement will be
announced via @cer lab instastory
every day every 00 pm Well,
back again after hearing the information
earlier, apparently there are already a lot of questions,
Mas Mbak and also Ma'am in the q&a column Well
here it seems that Ee is interested, yes,
enthusiastic to ask further
about this fbd insurance once again
I want to remind colleagues
not to get confused to send
questions in the q&a column not in the
chat column like that okay maybe I will
read it first for the
first question Are Mrs. Faiza Budwi
and also Mr. Michael ready to
answer question I Okay okay maybe
Mbak Ayti will eh will read the q&a
Sis or eh I
can just do it eh is okay Mbak Z Okay Okay
Thank you Mbak for
this first question Eh I will give it to
Mas Michael the question is from Farel
Alono
eh thank you Mas Michel for a
very insightful presentation  I'm
curious One form of protection is
insurance, right Where is this There are many forms,
starting from personal protection and assets
Is there a kind of R ofs that can be
used as a reference regarding the priority of
protection, what form needs to be
prioritized Thank you in advance,
maybe you can answer Mas Michel, please
Okay, thank you Eh Thank you yael yes Eh
this is a very good question, right Eh I'm
sure eh If friends,
maybe we talk about protection, it's quite
long, but hopefully ee I can
simplify it, yes friends,
so ee if we talk about
protection priorities Okay, there are
many protections, yes, but I always package the
protection, there are only four friends,
yes, there are only four protections, the
first is protection for Estate
or for Inheritance assets and
friends, the second is protection
for income protection, the third
is for education protection, the
fourth is old age protection, so
if we talk about priorities, then if
today we talk to
friends who are G, if we talk to
friends who are G, the
first priority is to
have
income, yes, friends have a
sekangikik PR, right
Gat Temi
inome
and the first big one So
if suddenly Eh  because of pollution, right?
Yes, in Jakarta, ISPA requires a
large cost, so it can be covered without
having to take from our cash flow.
Second, make sure that the protection you
have can
provide a replacement income when
you are no longer productive. So,
roughly, after that, we will find out what
kind of protection there is. Well, there
will definitely be several types of protection,
but once again, you
must have four protections. The first is,
if I were to prioritize
income protection first, friends,
have that first after your
cash flow has been sorted out. Have an
emergency fund. Okay, once again, emergency funds
and protection are different, friends,
emergency funds and protection are different,
emergency funds mean talking
about, ee, something that is there for
emergencies and is very liquid, so
whenever you need it, you can
take it, but you also have to have protection,
so income protection first,
income protection, then maybe later, friends, you
can start,
eh, adding more protection for your old age
because protection, protection for your old age
should be able to be able to do it at the same time as
friends start working because
the key is, ee, set aside
some of our expenses for our
parents later, who depend on
us, who we are.
then start to be able to enter into protection for
ee education later for
our next generations and
also Estate or inheritance protection hopefully
answer
Thank you well thank you very much Mr.
Michael for the answer hopefully
answer Yes to Brother Farel earlier for
his question and next
Eh there is a question for Mrs. Faiz and also
Budwi regarding how to
negotiate a salary that can produce a
win-win solution to recruiters And
also how to communicate
about career ladder opportunities to
recruiters as a form of loyalty
to the organization or company
Thank you maybe it can be
answered by Mrs. Faiza or Budi please let
me first later Sis will be added yes
as first eh as someone who
has applied like that at the beginning of his career If
by chance if later J actually Eh by
default if your career is
good enough there will be head
Hunters who try to recruit
you
Eh actually maybe the
first one eh yes Eh your salary negotiation you
have to know the market price too that's why
the network has to be wide friends
must know actually for the levels
that I want to apply this e how much is the
average that can also be asked to eh
to the recruiter but we want this
from the start  Asked also this is actually the
average, check the market too,
so what is the win-win? According to
friends, it seems like, eh, earlier, the
grass is greener on the other side, right,
as Michael said. Well, that can
also be checked. Do we reflect on
ourselves, eh, is there any
value of ours that can be, eh,
more value compared to our competitors,
like that, eh, compared to
other prospective employees, ee, what
we can offer to the company, we
have to know very, very strongly,
that position for that industry is
what is most needed. Well, that
was a chat first, yes, check the market
first, check the waves, then how to communicate
career opportunities to recruiters, yes, it's
okay to ask, right, in fact,
usually recruiters like it if we are
also Eager, there is a desire to know
actually later here, in terms of
career levels, how is the structure,
how is it, friends, you can see the
structure, usually if there is a
promotion, most of them are from within or
recruit from outside, that's okay,
it shows that friends are
actually very interested in
ee with the position that  Friends,
try to apply like that and show that
friends are people who also have
eh a good eh
ambition, it's different between having ambition  I am
equally ambitious, yes Well, having ambition
is good, it is a sign that you are
people who know what
you want What is it from my and
EE's perspective, I am the leader who will try to
recruit people, yes I also see that
potential from people, if from Radu,
can I add something?
Okay, from me, as Kak F
said, it is very important for
friends during the
interview process, you can
ask about the career ladder of
this position, where is it, and eh, from the perspective of
career growth or or what is the career leader
like, you can
ask and of course we will be
happier, eh, friends who want to know
in the organization, eh, this candidate
or eh, prospective e employee,
where will he be and what will he have, eh, what is the Aim
for eh, eh, what will he be
like next, so we will be very
happy if anyone also asks
about what is the career ladder called, eh, and
then it was related to eh,
the question, eh, in relation to eh,
what is it, eh, Kak
Zata, Okay, so for the question earlier,
regarding eh, the form, eh, how do
communicating about Puang
Pur's career path as a form of loyalty
to the organization or company Sis
okay well if of course from the side of
eh what is it called eh loyalty as a
form eh eh related to reality to the
company eh what is certain is
friends when friends eh what is it
called in the company are given
good development and where what eh
friends fulfillment that can be
obtained from a company of course
will eh indirectly
friends will engage with the
company that is certain
friends must identify the
company and
its going concern What is it like because when
friends work ee friends
make sure that friends have
security or a sense of comfort being in the
organization For example does
the organization provide friends eh
eh can be Open or can express
opinions if that is the need of
friends because one of
our organization one of the values
is how we are Open How
we can express opinions
is one of the values ​​that are in
FD so when friends ee can
express friends' opinions and
that is one of the needs of
friends and fulfillment
can be related to development it is very
important to be able to ee what is it called
friends stay in  an organization like
that Okay thank you very much for
the answer earlier Mrs. Faiza and also Budwi
who EE also earlier Eh Mr. Michael has
helped answer the first question too
but Eh it's a shame because of
time constraints the question earlier
also became the closing of
our discussion session today sir So we
apologize for the questions
from all of you who have not been
answered, maybe we can also help
answer live eh here later
if there are still those that we can answer
we will help Answer yes Ms. Zata yes
Okay Okay thank you very much Mrs. Eh Okay
thank you for the answer earlier which
has eh helped us to Malih
a lot of information and get to know
more about fbd insurance and earlier we
not only learned information
about fbd insurance but we also eh
learned about eh the importance of
soft skills to money sense in Gen
today like that Well before closing
this session and parting with all of you
Is there a closing message
that you would like to convey to
your colleagues by eh Mr. Michael Mrs. Faiza
and also Mrs. Dwi to your colleagues present
and Ms. Audition Maybe I would like
to add to eh a closing message
to your colleagues, please from
Who's first okay from me maybe
okay eh friends ee friends
make sure to prepare yourselves
because to start a career of course eh
friends also eh choose a company
that is lining with your vision friends
for example in our fwd the vision is
changing the way People feel about
insurance a very powerful vision and
how we in it can eh can
change that vision well of course
friends also have to prepare
themselves what is needed maybe
related ee what is it called eh skills to
communicate How to adapt and
of course How to collaborate that's all
for eh
friends Okay thank you very much Mrs.
Dwi for the up maybe from Faiz Mas
Michael and also
Mbak Mas Michael first okay I
Okay eh maybe
eh I apologize if I can't answer
everything yes earlier yes but if ee from
me ee of course there will definitely be a
lot of questions How to
wisely manage finances answer only one
k responsibility with the
financial decisions that friends have taken
if friends have dared to take ee
decided to take this yes
friends must be responsible and
then the next is the second one yes the
second is besides that also
make sure friends already have  ee
back plan so t earlier I had a chance
ee someone saw ee
asked how to protect and all
kinds of protection like this backup
plan friends like emergency exit like
that yes You already have a plan but you
can have a plan B like that yes and the
last one friends and make sure yes
when n friends
eh enter into eh the
real world like that Yes make sure it is
in accordance with your passion friends because
ee when we do everything
with passion then surely in the future it
will be much better than me
thank you okay thank you very much
Mas Michael for the next Mrs. Faiza
maybe will add for e
closing Pan closing please I I
still try to answer Yes my
juniors so I tried to answer
also earlier in QS some I have answered
like that three questions ee maybe
the message if you are still FR graduate it's
okay Try first like that and starting
from Tu right I answered there earlier there was
someone asked I don't know what
my talent is like that try to reflect
first what sport what is the
easiest most Happy when doing what
yeah don't just play games yeah
because it's a bit difficult yeah if you are happy
tapungk
good new game like that right but
the point is suu eh always learning like that yes
self development is very important like that
because once again our competition is not
only in ee Indonesia but also with
eh resources from
abroad that friends have to
know and even though Okay we in
Indonesia only know Indonesian
but eh if I may add
English at least add one isas
like that because ee We will not be
able to communicate with the outside world
when the international language used
we can ee use so
Okay if you can't speak five languages ​​it's okay just
one if I may if
I may add a message at least
English ee if you can't ee active
passive ee it's a must because no matter
what we will be
in contact with the outside world too so
that's the soft skills that were added by Kak Dwi
Kak Michael that's just an addition from
me like that thank you ready to be involved
in the world of
work Okay Okay thank you very much Mrs.
Faiza for the closing message earlier for
e Ms. Ayudisti maybe there's
another additional message Miss may maybe ee
I won't rap up the Soft skills
yes because earlier ah rapped up with Mbak
Faiza Badwi and also Mas Michael eh what's
his name I just want to add this
friends Eh maybe there are some who are curious
about fwd insurance and it
seems like you want to try working at fwd like that
Well friends maybe you
've been informed that we have a career
page here at uicp in the career lab Like that Ee
we have many programs
for fresh graduates especially eh one
is fix nah fix that is fwd
internship experience and also eh dgp
or digital graduate program or that
is eh fwd management training program
So friends if for example
you want to experience working in a
multinational company like that so the
company is already international huh
Eh try working at fbd it's really exciting huh
So friends if for example you
want to experience what it's called How do you
learn to work in a
company well that's a really good
program to start your career
friends namely in fix or fwd
internship experience and also in
digital gaduate program so you can just go
straight to  what is it called eh applied
like that on the e website kar laab and
uicc like that yeah later we will eh try to
sort and if for example friends are
interested like that yeah we can call for an
interview like that Well to fix it ourselves
we will start in February like that
so friends eh what is it called if
for example the time is right eh looking for an
internship like that yeah we eh what is it called will
start the program in February 2024 like that
So we will start
interviewing and also sourcing in
December and also January for Yeah but
for the dig program or Man train
we will start in March 2024 So
friends if for example those who graduate this year
then want to go
straight like that yeah can also go to the Man
training
prr said so that's all until
we meet friends Hopefully later it will be
a match to enter
[Music]
F for the closing message as
ee the last message
this afternoon so if friends eh want to
be mas-mas or ma-mbak SCBD
eh you can go directly to bu ui cise
carlab at
carlab.co/putuicisefwd like that well
once again I would like to thank
Mas Michel Bu Faiza and also Bu
Dwi and Mbak yudisti for the time and
information shared today
we give appreciation to all friends
to ladies and gentlemen and also ee Mas badi
fbd insurance Okay, please go
to Mas Michael Bu Faiza budwi and
Mbak ayudisti if you want to leave the
Zoom meeting to continue
your activities after this thank you and
hopefully we can meet again on another
occasion Thank you all Thank you yes
Zata okay
thank you see you dibd
See you at
okay well colleagues don't leave yet
because as
mentioned earlier there will be
an announcement of the best questioner in
this session so after eh sorted earlier
for the best questioner congratulations to Kak
FR Sinaga who became the best questioner
in the session with fbd insurance this afternoon
for Kak FR Sinaga can directly
send the name email address and also
cellphone number to the panelists on zoom yes
Sis Well next I would like to
remind colleagues to
confirm their attendance on the QR Code
that  is on the following screen and also
provide feedback via the QR Code
on the screen as a requirement to
get a certificate well when filling out the
form also have to be re-confirmed that
for eh writing the name and also the
email address for Eh writing it correctly
so that the certificate can be delivered
properly to your email friends
so It's really okay to take a photo or
fill in the confirmation link for attendance and
feedback as soon as possible and
colleagues for those who want to get
information can also join
the unitysapp group the link will
be on the final page of colleagues
and of course I want to
invite colleagues to
suendkaniku
event
chis.caralab.co/event because there is an
opportunity to get to know and
register for more than 100
companies and of course get
various training and also
free webinars well colleagues can access
Instagram @ karespo.ui for further information
not only Wi colleagues
can also find out information about
career workshops and also other interesting events
that are more on
LinkedIn and also Instagram
@ c and colleagues are also really welcome
to join the WhatsApp community uise group
at
klap.co/u-2ag because there colleagues
can get the latest INF regarding
the series of events
and it's time for us to say goodbye,
friends. We would like to
thank you for your enthusiastic presence
in today's session. We
hope this activity can be
beneficial for all of you. Not
only that, we would also like to
thank the sponsors of Expo 2023,
namely Bang Niaga Paragon Technology and
Innovation, PT Pegadaian, Bank Danamon and
Bank Mandiri, and our official media
partners, namely Untar radio, duniaui
events.ina events.bangat, tvui bfbui bmf
UI disnakarja mading.id, UI humans
and xui who have supported the smooth running
until today. Lastly, I, Z,
as moderator, Pit, I will leave.
Peace be upon you, warahmatullahi
wabarakatuh, Expo 2023
prepare. Thank you and see you later.
Thank you. Indonesia is a nation that has a great
[Music]
right to
great hopes. Starting from a big dream. We
present to you
Negeri
Paragon, a company from Indonesia
that started its business in the
cosmetics sector since
[Music]
1985 [
Music]
until now.  Paragon has given birth to
Warda makeover
Emina
kalf
Putri
kristalion
insterfect
labor
ta
Wonder OMG
and with his permission now we are
growing and continuing to
grow Paragon has a
20 hectare factory which is divided into tu
[Music]
areas
have 43 distribution centers and
marketing offices spread
throughout Indonesia and in
Malaysia We always work together with
more than 10,000
employees our step to reach the
future is to become a
company that has the best management through
quality that provides benefits for
Mit society and
[Music]
our environment a group of ordinary people
who have endless enthusiasm
if all the values ​​​​of Christianity are
carried out and with the help of Allah
subhahu wa taal Insyaallah we will
[Music]
evolve endlessly and
human development goes hand in hand like
fate if it stops then it will die
Paragon will continue to develop
its talents if Mere develops then we
will also develop currently we continue to
grow to be
big the development of a company that is
very dependent on the speed of capturing TR
BR Paragon comes with modernity that has
become 39 times since
2010 we have become a market leader in the
cosmetics industry for  make up category
in Indonesia our products sold
7 pieces per
Bukit we also received various
awards such as the halal
top brand award Indonesian best brand
Award and 25 influential women in
the field of entrepreneurship in Asia according to
magazines
[Music]
now we are transforming into a
holding company Paragon k which has
three business pillars the first pillar Paragon
universa utama or paraversa which
has a subsidiary Paragon
Technology and Innovation a
cosmetics company that has become a market
leader Parama Global inspira or
paramah our distribution company Faros
Citra International or a
beauty company that was founded to
reach more consumers and
paranova global Optima or paranova
a company with a reseller business model
to bring
wider benefits to the community and bring
Paragon to be more Beyond
business and pharmacore Technology and
Innovation alone is
entitled the second pillar Paragon beneva
Investama or beneva which focuses on
investment and MC berhayati subakat
entrepreneurship Institute our third pillar
which focuses on incubation and
acceleration
[Music]
our business also contributes to the
country based on the first four pillars of
education including Paragon
scholarship Novo Club teacher training program
through ardpiring
teacherpiring lect program and good
leader good teacher second health
with  promoting and providing
education on clean and healthy lifestyles in
three environments, one of which is the
provision of clean water on the walls of
Sumba, Keemp, empowering women
through the Women Space program and the
community development program for inspiring villages
[Music]
Praise be to God, together
we encourage our hearts, encourage our spirits,
encourage our dreams for a better Indonesia
[Music] we were
born different, but above
that difference, in essence, we have
similarities, humans must be different, various
ethnicities, cultures and backgrounds,
but the differences that exist around us are
actually the driving force for us to
remain united and united, we are like a
collection of puzzles that have
different shapes, colors and pictures,
if arranged correctly, will
display extraordinary work.
My name is James, I am from customer
experience consumer banking, my
current position is as CX governance and
improvement process, we can see that
related to the composition of employees
at CMB Niaga, there are old, young,
menials, and
so on, I am always amazed by the way
Cim biniaga unites differences, it's really cool, there is no
discrimination because of
ethnicity, religion, or ethnic background,
respect, my name is Friska, currently
my position is as business learning head in the
subdirectorate of HR learning and
development, in the beginning when I joined  with
si baga I felt a little
insecure because most of my experience is not
in the HR world but si binaga could
be the right place to
explore myself because it has
Epic corporate values ​​that focus on
enabling Talent I have been working at SIM
biniaga since the first year I joined
I feel cm biniaga is a company
that consistently applies the principles of
diversity and inclusiveness while working
here I feel very comfortable there is
never any feeling of discrimination always
given the same opportunity and that is
what makes me able to work optimally
and wholeheartedly as part of the
customer experience team I always
put the needs of customers as
the main thing this is also in line with
my passion from a larger scope
shembinaga consists of a
multicultural team with diverse
backgrounds but fighting for one goal
like our country's motto in Neka
Tunggal Ika In my opinion diversity
can actually be an added value and
competitive advantage because there is no
Superman in the real world there is
super
at Cim biaga we prioritize diversity
and inclusivity every difference that exists
around us is actually a strength
to reach a higher level
[Music]
growing is not a goal
but growing is a
journey of daring to leave the
comfort zone and grasp Global exposure
with both
hands the best performance and never
give up we need  say Yes even though it's
not easy and swallow a lot of no's
until finally Yes to grow
further we need to be together because
when you grow we all also
use every opportunity and achieve your
future to continue to grow you need the
right environment a place to achieve
your well-being a place that gives you
space to continue to grow what your goals are
and always stay in
control Come on get up take control and
Let's
[Music]
grow
[Applause]
foreign